<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Force.com | Deepak Kapoor]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.deepakkapoor.net/blog/categories/force-dot-com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.deepakkapoor.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-23T22:24:36+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.deepakkapoor.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Deepak Kapoor]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Connecting to Force.com from IDE]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.deepakkapoor.net/2010/12/13/connecting-to-force-com-from-ide/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-13T00:00:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.deepakkapoor.net/2010/12/13/connecting-to-force-com-from-ide</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Working through Force.com tutorials I came to the point where I wrote some Apex code. Instead of doing this via Browser based interface, I decided to use Force.com IDE which as you know is an Eclipse plugin. This post documents the steps I went through to get connectivity to the warehouse application created as part of the tutorial.</p>

<p>I created a new Force.com project in IDE and entered my username and password.</p>

<p><img src="https://googledrive.com/host/0B6PDO8HPEQZNZWpTRms0ZWtlaUU/uploads/2010/12/201012101021.jpg" alt="201012101021.jpg" width="480" height="472" /></p>

<p>Things did not go well and I got the following message.</p>

<p><img src="https://googledrive.com/host/0B6PDO8HPEQZNZWpTRms0ZWtlaUU/uploads/2010/12/201012101025.jpg" alt="201012101025.jpg" width="480" height="225" /></p>

<p>But I thought that I already have a security token. I&rsquo;ve been logging into developer.force.com from this computer. However I decided to follow the suggestion in the message and logged into developer.force.com and went through the Reset Security Token process.</p>

<p><img src="https://googledrive.com/host/0B6PDO8HPEQZNZWpTRms0ZWtlaUU/uploads/2010/12/201012131251.jpg" alt="201012131251.jpg" width="480" height="200" /></p>

<p>I got the token emailed to me and used is as per the instructions on Reset Security Token page. The instruction is to append the token to the password.</p>

<p>And finally I was connected.</p>

<p><img src="https://googledrive.com/host/0B6PDO8HPEQZNZWpTRms0ZWtlaUU/uploads/2010/12/201012131248.jpg" alt="201012131248.jpg" width="480" height="472" /></p>

<p>I could now see my project in the project explorer.</p>

<p><img src="https://googledrive.com/host/0B6PDO8HPEQZNZWpTRms0ZWtlaUU/uploads/2010/12/201012101037.jpg" alt="201012101037.jpg" width="323" height="265" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Era of Cloud Computing Consultant]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.deepakkapoor.net/2008/12/04/the-era-of-cloud-computing-consultant/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-04T00:00:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.deepakkapoor.net/2008/12/04/the-era-of-cloud-computing-consultant</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img style="border-top-width: 0px; border-left-width: 0px; float: left; border-bottom-width: 0px; border-right-width: 0px" height="109" alt="image" src="https://googledrive.com/host/0B6PDO8HPEQZNZWpTRms0ZWtlaUU/uploads/2008/12/image1.png" width="150" border="0" /> <strong>CCC stands for Cloud Computing Consultant</strong>. There, I have said it. This is my contribution to acronyms-land. I have also cleverly designed it to minimize <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Repetitive_strain_injury">RSI</a> which I am sure will be appreciated. You only have to use one key to type the acronym. If you ever come across the term Cloud Computing Consultant then remember that you read about it on <a href="http://www.debugrelease.com/">One .Net Way</a>. Before you start googling this out let me make few things clear. IBM has a service called Cloud Computing Consulting which is more of a practice. <strong>Cloud Computing Consultant</strong> on the other hand is about an <strong>individual</strong>. </p>


<p>  <p>&#160;</p>  <h4>So who is a CCC? </h4>  <p>He or she (if girls get interested in this stuff) is a person who sucks up the knowledge and complexity from Cloud vendors (Microsoft in my case) and translates it into real world English for his clients. </p>  <p>&#160;</p>  <h4>Why do we need him?</h4>  <p>Good question. I am glad you asked it. No I seriously am. We need him for the same reasons we need tech consultants today. He is skilled and knowledgeable to recommend, advise and also implement business solutions based on Cloud Computing. CCS (Cloud Computing Solution) to be more precise. There, I&rsquo;ve done it again. For the records; the term CCS also calls OneDotNetWay its birthplace.</p>  <p>&#160;</p>  <h4>Should you become one?</h4>  <p>If you are a night programmer who sacrifices luxuries of life such as television, sleep etc. to keep yourself up to date with new technologies then I highly recommend it. This is where the industry is heading. Of course if you are a maintenance programmer who is willing to spend rest of his years working on an application which went into support mode a decade ago then you can skip the whole cloud thing.</p>  <p>&#160;</p>  <h4>How do you get started?</h4>  <p>A lot of it depends on what is your learning style. But this is what I would suggest. Leave not a single unread word on <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/azure/default.mspx">Microsoft Azure site</a> and to everything else linked from here. Once you have done that, I recommend watching all <a href="https://sessions.microsoftpdc.com/public/timeline.aspx">PDC videos</a> on Azure. By this time you will be ready and excited to check out the Cloud for yourself. To do just that you can <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/azure/sdk.mspx">download Azure SDK</a> and also <a href="https://connect.microsoft.com/SelfNomination.aspx?SiteID=681&amp;ProgramID=2500&amp;pageType=1">ask for access to CTP</a>. Microsoft will be more than happy to provide one. I got mine in less than a day. Finally keep visiting <a href="http://www.deepakkapoor.net/">DeepakKapoor.net</a>.</p>  <p>All the best.</p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
